jonwaraas.com 2016-10-12

# Privacy Policy - Jon Waraas

**PURPOSE OF POLICY:** Handshake LLC dba JonWaraas.com (“us,” “we,” or “Company”) is committed to respecting the privacy rights of its visitors and users of this website (the “Site”). We created this Privacy Policy (“Policy”) to give you confidence as you visit and use the Site, and to demonstrate a commitment to fair information practices and the protection of privacy.

If you visit our Site then you accept the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

We are not responsible for the privacy of any information you reveal or post in any public forum (e.g., blog comments), or for the privacy practices of websites that are operated or owned by third parties.

**I. Here’s What We Collect**

**A. Information You Provide to Us.**

We collect personally identifiable information from you only if you sign up for a newsletter or contact us including:

Your name,

Your email address, and

Your website URL, and

Message details you send with inquiries.

**B. Privacy Policy Modifications and Updates.** We may update and modify this Privacy Policy. If we modify or update the policy, we will post a notice on the Site for 30 days prior to the change going into effect.

**C. Effective Date:** The effective date of this new privacy policy shall be June 2, 2015.

**D. Third Party Tracking:** As a matter of transparency, we’ve decided to disclose to you whether third parties can acquire and track your personally identifiable information through our website. Google and other sites listed below can track you through this Site as we use their services for social media and infrastructure purposes. Google participates in the NIA opt out program. You can visit [this link](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) to no longer be tracked by Google and Google properties such as Google Plus. You can also visit the following sites to read their privacy policies and how they track individuals across the web: 

You can use programs such as [Privacy Badger](https://www.eff.org/privacybadger) to further control the collection of information regarding you online.

**F. Information We Collect Automatically:** When you visit our Site, we automatically receive and store information about your visit on our servers. Our servers log your IP address, your page requests at our Site, and other information collected from “cookies”. A cookie is a small file that is sent to your computer’s browser or your mobile device when you visit a website. Cookies remain on your computer or device until they are deleted and tell us, for example, how you arrived at our Site (including search engines and search terms), how you navigate around our Site (including what articles you search for and browse), and what products or services you purchase.

We also use cookies to to serve direct personalized marketing from JonWaraas.Com (including on other web sites). As explained in Section V of this Privacy Policy, most browsers allow you to block or reject cookies, although this may impact your ability to use features of our Site. JonWaraas.Com may combine information collected via cookies with Personal Information provided by you.

Along with cookies, we may deliver “web beacons” through our Site and/or e-mails to you which are associated with third-party advertising networks. Web beacons (also called “pixel tags”) are small graphic images that may not be visible to Site visitors that collect information about the usage of the Site on an anonymous basis. We may use web beacons in emails to determine device-type and learn if emails have been delivered and opened. JonWaraas.Com may also combine information from web beacons with Personal Information provided by you.

Web beacons also allow advertising networks to serve you JonWaraas.Com advertisements when you visit other websites. For example, a web beacon logs the articles you view at our Site, and then shows you an ad for similar articles from JonWaraas.Com when you browse to another website. Because your web browser receives advertising from the advertising network’s servers, these companies may set, view, or edit their own cookies or web beacons. Please note that we do not control the policies of any third parties, including the privacy policies of advertising networks.

**II. E-mails We Send**

If you place an order, create an account with us, or otherwise provide us your e-mail address, we may use that address to confirm your order, confirm the creation of an account, or to notify you of important information or changes to your account or our policies and practices.

In addition, we (or one of our affiliated stores/websites) may send you information about special offers, new products and services, system changes, and other information we think may be of interest to you. We own multiple brands/stores, and if you sign up with one brand/store, you are automatically subscribed to all the others and may receive emails from any of our brands. If you do not wish to receive these e-mails, you may “opt-out” or “unsubscribe” from these e-mails by following the instructions contained in the e-mail. You may also opt-out of receiving these e-mails during the ordering or registration process.

Our Site includes “e-mail to a friend” functionality that allows you to easily share product or other valuable information with your friends and family. Any e-mail addresses provided to us in the use of these features are used solely for the intended purpose of the e-mail communication you authorize. We do not retain these e-mail addresses in our database.

**III. How We Use and Share your Personal Information**

Examples of when we may share Personal Information include:

• in order to provide services (e.g., ping tool) that you have requested;  
• when we believe in good faith that it is necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or to comply with law;  
• when we believe in good faith that it is necessary to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;  
• when we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use, or as otherwise required by law;  
• if JonWaraas.Com is acquired by or merged with another organization, Personal Information would be one of the assets transferred to or acquired by a third party;  
• We may publicly disclose the name, city, and state of the contest and sweepstakes winners; and  
• with our affiliated brands and stores (unless you have opted out of our doing so).

We may also provide anonymized information to our partners, including, for example, our marketing, testing, personalization and analytics partners. Our partners help us better understand how often and in what ways people use our Site, so that we, and our partners, can provide you with the best experience. For example, we may place a cookie on your browser or mobile device that records the products you viewed at our Site, and then provide that information, in an anonymized form only, to a third-party partner, to allow such partner to show you ads for similar products that are available from us.

**IV. You’ve Got Choices**

While the Site does not respond to a web browser’s “Do Not Track” signal, JonWaraas.Com offers its customers choices with regard to its use and disclosure of Personal Information. These options include opting out of online behavioral advertising provided by JonWaraas.Com or from our third-party marketing partner(s), or choosing for us not to share Personal Information with third parties.

Of course, you are always free to not disclose information to us. In addition, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete cookies as soon as you leave our Site. Additionally, you can disable or delete similar data used by browser add-ons, by changing the add-on’s settings, or visiting the Web site of its manufacturer. Although you are not required to accept cookies or provide us information when you visit our sites, if you set your browser to reject cookies (or decide not to provide us certain information) you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of this Site.

**V. Links to Other Sites**

Our Site may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites. If you follow a link to another site, you should read that site’s privacy policy. The inclusion of any link does not imply our endorsement of the external site company, its website or websites, or the products or services it promotes or sells. When you leave our Site to visit one of these linked sites, the only information transferred to the third party is the fact that you came from our Site.

JonWaraas.Com is not responsible or liable for the independent privacy policies of these third-party websites. You should consult the privacy policies at these websites to determine how your information may be collected, stored and used.

**VI. Children’s Privacy**

Our Site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

**VII. You can “Opt Out” and/or Correct Your Personal Information**

Upon your request, we will:

• correct or update your Personal Information;  
• stop sending emails to your email address or catalogs or other mailings to your physical address; and/or  
• disable your account to prevent future purchases through that account.

Please do not email us your credit-card number or other sensitive personal information.

**VIII. DMCA CLAIM DISCLOSURES** We comply with the Digital Millennium Copyright Act of 1998, better known as the “DMCA”. Should we receive a claim of copyright infringement, we will comply with the safe harbor requirements of the DMCA. Part of that compliance may require the disclosure of your identity if you are either the allegedly infringing party or the party filing the copyright infringement complaint.

**XI. Questions?**

If you have any questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by [emailing us here](http://www.jonwaraas.com/contact-jon-waraas/).
